♪Shrugging off past burdens♪
♪Beneath the mask, who am I?♪
♪Release and find wider shores♪
♪Love's a riddle, and rain pours heavy♪
♪Crossed paths, now downward fall♪
♪From dust arises starlight's spark♪
♪Tearing through
the night's dense blockade♪
♪Heart's flame illuminates all solitude♪
♪Let time's sails drift endlessly♪
♪Through wandering exile♪
♪Breaking free from the cocoon,
I start anew♪
♪Moon as song, life as flame♪
♪Nameless heart clings fiercely♪
♪Let me♪
♪Charge toward the next raging river♪
♪Moon darts, snow falls♪
♪We tread rugged paths to reunite♪
♪Hands held tight♪
♪We forever live for love's sake♪
♪Shadow's spear burns fiercely♪
=Legend of The Female General=
=Episode 34=
Under war's shadow,
people always suffer most.
If peace reigns,
I'd gladly retire.
But I intend to be a great general.
How about this?
I'll support you.
Thank you, General Feihong.
Li Kuang returns to Rundu today.
It should be about time now.
I'll see him off.
Don't you want me to go?
Better not.
Li Kuang got startled
by Mr. Cheng's
grand display.
If not for me,
he'd be long gone.
Send the betrothal certificate?
Give it to me.
Cheng Lisu, hey you!
You have
peanut allergy!
Why eat peanut cakes?
Taotao, I...
You remembered my peanut allergy?
Is this really the time for that?
How much you ate?
I'd rather check your pulse.
Your pulse is steady.
You lie to me?
Taotao, I don't.
You care about me too much.
Yes. I care about you and fall for you.
So what?
Give me the thing.
Why stand up?
Song Taotao, I want to marry you.
I love you.
I, Cheng Lisu, have
fallen for you,
wishing to marry you.
To tie the nuptial knot
and travel together,
writing books and tasting herbs.
I'll only marry you.
What do you think?
I don't want
to tie the nuptial knot.
I'll be lovebirds with you,
so we can travel around.
Right, lovebirds.
Albizia flowers?
They calm the mind and the nerve,
symbolizing marital bliss.
Taotao,
together with you,
I seek no dramatic love.
I only want peace and joy
with you.
It's the wedding invitation
of the Chengs and Songs.
Lisu and Taotao will
marry this month's end.
So fast?
Their families
have done almost
everything of betrothal.
Naturally it is fast.
Finally,
they could be together.
Yes, they are.
Then when will you
and Miss He end up together?
This loquat tree is still here?
So short.
Huaijin.
Must you show off
in front of me,
and then mock my height?
Back then,
you were so cold.
But I'm lucky.
I remember once
when I failed an exam,
I was locked in a dark room.
(I was starving at the time.)
(And then)
(someone secretly gave me loquats.)
I really like
such a kind soul.
You like him
over some loquats?
It's me who gave you
those loquats.
So it was you, Huaijin.
I knew it.
You're the only one
I've ever been so in sync with.
You're truly a lifesaver.
Look at you.
How could you be last again?
Master Wei.
You taught us self-sacrifice.
If I don't endure hardship, who will?
You!
Hopeless.
(Xianchang Academy)
What?
Can't you face me properly?
Xiao Jue.
You are my most proud student.
Why did you...?
Why did he end up liking me?
A woman
disguised as a man
and studied here.
That was outrageous.
You even went
to join the military.
How absurd!
How immoral!
How rude!
Xiao Jue has always
maintained good conduct.
It must be you
who lured him astray.
- Master Wei.
- Master...
I fell for her first.
She is Wei's
first female general.
Frankly speaking,
I'm the lucky one.
You're a grown man.
Don't always talk
about love.
Beauty brings disaster.
So they are
General Feihong and Fengyun?
Yes!
I'll be a general too!
- Me too!
- I'll be a general!
Stop it!
Don't mess around.
Return to your studies!
- Yes.
He's a walking contradiction.
When he heard General Feihong
was a woman,
he angrily removed
the calligraphy
she left during her studies.
But then he still
hung it back up.
Huaijin.
Did you
take me here on purpose?
You're no longer
the problem student,
but the Xianchang Academy's pride.
However,
General Feihong,
to preserve your dignity,
should you study
and retake the exam?
(He Rufei, C)
Retaking the exam for this
would be truly shameful.
Besides,
it's in the long past.
After joining the army,
I kept improving
and became a scholarly general.
I master the classics long ago.
The Virtue chapter?
Unshaken by external things.
How's it, father?
Did I do it well?
Huaijin, if you wish,
I can...
No need.
I mean,
to recite the Virtue chapter again.
What's on your mind?
Lanterns for sale!
Take a look.
Beautiful lanterns!
Lanterns!
Come see!
Lanterns for sale!
All varieties available!
This is my first time
at Yaojing's Lantern Festival.
It's much livelier than
Water God Festival!
Your wish to wander,
my hand to hold.
Sugar figure.
Huaijin.
Want a sugar figure?
Buy you one.
Well,
one with a phoenix?
Or one with a Kylin?
No.
No?
I have money.
I'll buy you one.
No basket-shaped ones here.
You like baskets?
Someone made
a candy basket
for Mr. Chu in Jiyang City?
Are you
feeling jealous?
I never expected
that the mighty General Fengyun
would become so jealous.
I am jealous.
No matter how generous one is,
after falling for someone,
they'd be jealous easily.
Moreover,
he was up to something.
Back then,
he gave me a tassel.
You know
the hardest favors to repay
are kindness.
But
we are different.
We don't need
clear lines.
Just like you,
I'm also unwavering.
I won't love other man.
Come on.
Sir.
One sugar figure.
May I draw it myself?
Of course.
Here.
Done!
You can stop
being jealous.
But
this might be too large.
It's hard to carry.
Don't worry, miss.
We can deliver it
to your mansion.
Really?
Thank you so much.
This one.
How is it?
General Yan.
He Yan.
What a rare sight!
Never expected you
to stroll through night markets.
This must be
you wife, right?
(Xia Chengxiu, Yan He's Wife)
In Rundu,
General Yan mentioned you often.
And this
must be General He.
I've long heard of your fame.
Enough with the formalities.
Xiao Jue, you're here
for the lantern riddles too?
Then go solve
the riddles.
Look how many I've solved already.
He's not solving them,
but
I'll solve one for him.
Xiu, I want you to solve one for me too.
Alright.
Pick one.
(Lantern Riddles)
The blue one then.
This character is remarkable
with four strokes...
Where should I hang this lantern?
What's the perfect spot?
Here then.
Even sages would bow before it.
Wait!
Ten and one at the bottom,
and three on top.
It's "Lei".
Brilliant, miss!
This lantern is yours.
Thank you.
Sir.
Why is
hers nicer than mine?
Sir!
Hungry? Let's get sweet dumplings.
Fans for sale.
Huaijin.
Do you think
we're especially lucky today?
Indeed.
Sweet dumplings!
Let's eat.
Thank you.
You two share one bowl
of sweet dumplings
at the Lantern Festival.
Wish you sweet and blissful,
and be a perfect couple.
Couple?
Us two.
You sweet talker.
(Foguang Temple)
Wait here. I'll give you flowers.
♪Light shines upon my heart♪
♪Unveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstream♪
♪The resonance of courage
rings loud and clear♪
♪It's the boldness
that defines existence♪
You once said
that you walked alone for so long,
yet no one noticed you
or cared about you.
So today,
I've scheduled everything.
I want
to walk through everything
you did with you.
♪Destiny is my creed♪
Therefore,
we revisited Xianchang Academy.
And that one-of-a-kind
lantern commemorating the past.
♪Charge ahead with blazing fervor♪
♪Stubbornly fighting with my life♪
You say the moon guides you,
but you
never need to borrow its light.
Because you can shine brightly
yourself.
He Yan.
I love you.
I wonder if you would like
to marry me.
♪The resonance of courage
rings loud and clear♪
♪It's the boldness
that defines existence♪
♪Chasing the light within my heart♪
What a coincidence.
I've been thinking the same.
♪You'll meet gazes where storms brew♪
♪With our unwavering true love,
brave the world with me♪
I'll be right there with you
through thick and thin.
We'll stick together
until we die.
♪Where is my home♪
♪Smile with tender charm♪
♪Take root and sprout♪
♪Shattered starlight♪
♪Crumbled into dust♪
♪Still gleaming with brilliance♪
♪I your eyes♪
♪My spirit lies♪
♪Soaring across the world's expanse♪
♪There must always be a longing♪
♪Disregard the wounds to seek the light♪
♪Light shines upon my heart♪
Except for sweet dumplings and lanterns,
you even make Feinu
release Kongming lanterns?
How thoughtful.
♪Chasing the light within my heart♪
♪Burying frailty,
embracing life through death♪
♪You'll meet gazes where storms brew♪
♪With our unwavering true love,
brave the world with me♪
(Chu Mansion)
This was a gift from her.
She said,
"Zilan" means nobility and purity.
Only those who love me
would give me such a name.
She gifted this to me.
She must have loved me.
Young Master,
look at this lantern.
Young Master.
(She loves me.)
She loves me.
She must have loved me.
Why did it shatter?
Why?
Why must it be
the very gift from her?
Young Master.
Why?
Why can't I
ever have anything I desire?
Young Master.
It's fate.
Why force it?
Young Master.
Then you'll draft
the edict.
Understood.
The plum blossoms in the tiny vase
radiate such vibrant fragrance.
Indeed.
This year's plum blooms
are really splendid.
Quite true.
The plum tree south of the city
is also in full bloom.
Yesterday,
General Fengyun went to pluck blossoms
for a young lady.
Xiao Jue?
For which young lady?
She is
no ordinary lady,
but General Feihong.
This
has become a romantic legend.
All agree the two generals
are destined.
Young nobles and ladies
now visit
the plum trees in pairs
to pray for blessings.
Indeed.
Fengyun and Feihong
truly make a peerless pair.
He Yan and Xiao Jue
make a peerless pair.
But General Feihong
and General Fengyun
can't be a good match.
What's different?
General Feihong and Fengyun
hold strong military forces.
It's quite special to be
on the rooftop at night.
When I was young,
before joining the army,
I loved the rooftops.
He Mansion's rooftop
was even higher.
My martial arts were poor.
I could only climb using ladders.
Once when I was halfway up,
I fell down.
Afraid of being noticed,
I didn't shout out.
For a long time after,
my back kept hurting.
Why love being on the rooftops?
Because they are high enough
to reach for the moon
and pluck stars
from the sky.
Childish.
What?
Everyone was so.
If you like it,
every rooftop in my mansion
will be yours.
Even after marriage,
okay?
Okay.
We'll climb together,
okay?
Okay.
If we need to bring snacks...
As long as you like it,
I'm okay.
What's funny?
I was thinking
the mighty General Fengyun
would climb roofs with me.
Moreover,
I regain control of the Fuyue Army.
You and the Xiao Army
might become obsolete.
Nothing keeping you busy?
Such bold words.
It matters not.
Merit determines
position.
I won't show any mercy.
Likewise.
Instead of this talk,
let's discuss
our wedding.
I've hired
Yaojing's best embroiderers
to make the bridal gown.
So soon?
Soon?
I think it's too slow.
Actually,
I feel the same.
I'll measure your shoulders.
Note this down.
Miss, raise your arm.
(You are a woman,)
(yet fight on the battlefields,)
(outshining all men.)
(You deserve)
(the title of)
(General Feihong.)
Why do you keep staring at me?
Beautiful.
You'll look even more stunning
in the wedding dress.
Why am I the only one being measured?
Marriage
is about us two.
Yes.
I need it too.
I want you to.
Me?
Your shoulders
are much broader than mine.
The waist.
Waist?
Measure with hands.
By the imperial decree,
summon General Fengyun Xiao Jue
to the palace.
Your Majesty.
Commander Xiao is here.
I'm Xiao Jue.
Greetings.
Rise.
I summoned you urgently
due to emerging circumstances.
Are the Wutuo people
making any movements?
Exactly.
I got tips from the border.
The Wutuo King had passed away.
His son succeeded the throne.
But his son
is too young.
While his uncle
has strong military forces,
eyeing covetously.
The officials
are divided into two factions.
The Wutuo
could erupt into civil war any moment.
The uncle has accumulated authority.
Usurping the throne
is just a matter of time.
To get more power,
given his warlike nature,
he'll surely invade the Wei.
You are absolutely right.
Therefore,
we shouldn't just watch idly.
Instead, we must prepare
in advance.
I think
we should discuss this with
General Feihong too.
Generals Fengyun and Feihong
are the twin stars of Wei.
With both of you here,
I can rest easy.
I'm flattered.
It's our duty
to protect the nation.
I heard
you gifted plum blossoms to He Yan.
Your Majesty,
He Yan and I
love each other.
We agreed...
Your Majesty,
Mr. Chu Zhao requests audience.
Let him in.
Yes.
By the imperial decree,
summon Mr. Chu Zhao!
- Your Majesty.
- Rise.
What brings you here?
I come here
for personal matters.
Why be so formal?
I've long admired a lady.
I boldly implore you to issue
a marriage decree.
Please grant me.
I see.
Which lady you admire?
Tell me.
He Yan.
You want to marry He Yan?
- Yes.
- No way!
Your Majesty,
He Yan and I are engaged.
And we're about to marry.
Without proper betrothal rites,
can you call it engagement?
Your Majesty,
I love He Yan...
I know.
You and He Yan
can marry.
But
General Fengyun and General Feihong
cannot.
Your Majesty.
I don't want to split lovebirds,
but I have my considerations.
If you insist on marrying He Yan,
I won't stop you.
But one of you
must surrender
your military authority.
Commander Xiao,
you fought so hard
to clear your father's name.
And the Xiao Army
barely regained
morale.
No one else
can command them.
Think it over.
Tomorrow,
tell me your answer.
Besides,
no outsiders shall know
about this matter.
Understood.
I admit.
I'm trying to
steal He Yan from you.
But concentrating
military power has been taboo.
He Yan suffered
so much pain
to reclaim her identity
as General Feihong.
Can you watch her give up
everything for you?
And how could you
betray your late father
and abandon the Xiao Army
he entrusted to you?
Xiao Jue,
just admit it.
You
and He Yan aren't destined.
You and her
cannot be together.
What took you so long?
What did His Majesty say?
The Wutuo King suddenly passed away,
succeeded by his young son.
Wutuo King's brother
is eyeing the throne for usurpation.
His Majesty fears
the Wutuo's civil war
will endanger
the Wei.
Therefore,
we must prepare in advance.
True.
We need to stay alert
of the cunning Wutuo people.
But,
for such crucial matters,
why did
His Majesty only summon you?
Next time,
His Majesty will summon you
to discuss this.
Excellent.
As the General Feihong,
you must soar freely
in the sky.
Young Master,
eat something.
I'm not hungry.
Leave now.
If you've made up your mind,
why being so troubled?
I am troubled?
Having served you for so long,
I can tell
you're troubled.
You resemble
glacial ice,
crystal clear,
yet chillingly cold.
Miss He
resembles fire,
shining brightly,
yet scorching
when you get close.
Today, you've spoken
too much.
I'm sorry.
Please eat.
Ice and fire cannot be together.
So what?
(Virtues' Enduring Legacy)
(Late Father Xiao Zhongwu,
Late Mother Song Wan)
(Constant effort)
(brings success.)
(Someday,)
(you two will become)
(Wei's Twin Stars.)
(Work together.)
(Wielding swords)
(to guard the land)
(and our people.)
(I believe I was born)
to be a general.
Sometimes, I even feel
I was a female general in my past life.
Impressive, right?
You know why I let you lead them?
Because
I'm unquestionably capable.
♪Before destiny is sealed♪
(Xiao Zhongwu, Song Wan)
Father, Mother.
I cannot abandon the Xiao Army.
Nor can I be her obstacle.
If we're not destined to be a couple...
♪That's my last wish♪
Then I'd rather be
single and alone.
♪Light shines upon my heart♪
♪Unveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstream♪
♪The resonance of courage
rings loud and clear♪
♪It's the boldness
that defines existence♪
♪I've seen the mountains♪
♪And trodden through ice♪
♪Day after day, I venture alone♪
♪Destiny is my creed♪
♪Ideals surge beneath the surface♪
♪Igniting the flame against the winds♪
♪A restless yearning in my soul♪
♪Gazing through the mire♪
♪Who cares about this boundless void♪
♪Charge ahead with blazing fervor♪
♪Stubbornly fighting with my life♪
♪Soaring across the world's expanse♪
♪There must always be a longing♪
♪Disregard the wounds to seek the light♪
♪Light shines upon my heart♪
♪Unveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstream♪
♪The resonance of courage
rings loud and clear♪
♪It's the boldness
that defines existence♪
♪Chasing the light within my heart♪
♪Burying frailty,
embracing life through death♪
♪You'll meet gazes where storms brew♪
♪With our unwavering true love,
brave the world with me♪
♪Soaring across the world's expanse♪
♪There must always be a longing♪
♪Disregard the wounds to seek the light♪
♪Light shines upon my heart♪
♪Unveiling scars,
I choose to swim upstream♪
♪The resonance of courage
rings loud and clear♪
♪It's the boldness
that defines existence♪
♪Chasing the light within my heart♪
♪Burying frailty,
embracing life through death♪
♪You'll meet gazes where storms brew♪
♪With our unwavering true love,
brave the world with me♪